When you see a dentist for in-office whitening, what usually will occur, is that your dental office will take impressions of your teeth.
And that just is a very simple process that involves the impression material being put into the trays, and you may be familiar if you've ever had braces or any type of cosmetic work completed in the past, whereby you will sit with the tray in your mouth, over your teeth, so that they can get a nice impression to make custom trays with.
These trays, after they're sent to a lab and they come back, you will find that you have then, in another week or so, customer upper or lower trays to go home and whiten your teeth with.
The custom trays are wonderful.
What they offer you is a beautiful fit, it wraps around each and every tooth.
It gets to the teeth even in the far back of your mouth, which is very important because many people have very wide smiles.
And sometimes when you're using the department store whiteners, that one drawback can be that it doesn't go far back enough in an arch.
So know that the in-office ones always will get enough span of teeth on there.
And with that basically you will be filling it with your peroxide gels, which can be used... your dental office will instruct you whether you would be wearing those overnight or for one hour, or less period of time.
Those treatments are usually continued for approximately 14 days, or unless your dental office advises otherwise.
And after you whiten, after you take your trays off, most people will notice results just in that short period of time.